Jahn Arellano

Comuna 2, Buenos Aires Province, Argentina



jahnarellano85@gmail.com



+543416181294



linkedin.com/in/jahnarellano

Summary

Experience focused on Brownfield and Greenfield projects using JVM languages like Java, Kotlin and Scala to build solutions like API RESTs applying agile methodologies, Having hands on tools like Maven, Gradle, Spring and others such as Docker, AWS. GCP, GIT, Jfrog, Sonar, Nexus. asynchronous process implemented on Kafka, applying techniques oriented to care code quality: peer programming, profiling, code review, clean code, check style, collaboration with teams with multiple profiles in order to solve, comunicate, push and making the things happen, always in continuous learning.

Experience



Back End Engineer

The Estée Lauder Companies Inc.

Oct 2020 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Client: Estee Lauder | Global Operations

Collaboration in the maintainance, rollout, implementation and go live of new features over a microservice architecture platform, assistance with product configuration tasks related, working with a multicultural, multi-regional team in multiple time zones, my role is a part of a cross-team providing BE and technical support for multiple internal customers.

Tech stack used: java 11, Bitbucket, AWS, Jenkins, GraphQL, Perl.



Back End Software Engineer

AgileEngine

Oct 2020 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Tech stack used: java 11, Bitbucket, AWS, Jenkins, GraphQL, Perl.



Backend Software Engineer

Oct 2021 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Tedalia LLC born as a Sofrware Factory Company to provide software solutions, created to provide my Backend engineer services as a freelance, delivering software solutions working in the design and development using Java, Kotlin and Scala.



Backend Software Engineer

Globant

Apr 2020 - Nov 2020 (8 months)

Client: Google Inc.® | Project: gBusiness®

Collaboration to deliver new features in micro services following EDA pattern using cutting edge stack of technologies like gRPC/Protobuf, Guice, Bazel, BloomRPC, GCP, Spanner.

Backend Software Engineer

Globant

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020 (6 months)

Client: OLX / naspersclassifieds | Berlin team - Staff Augmentation | Project: Panamera

Greenfield integration with PayU and PaymentsOS, using Kotlin, spring, gradle following a microservice architecture with EDA pattern, use of docker, project repositories and ci/cd on GitLab, as well using swaggerhub, jfrog and artifactory, care of checkstyle and code coverage. use of Kanban methodology.

Backend Software Engineer

Globant

Jul 2017 - Sep 2019 (2 years 3 months)

OLX Latam

Brownfield project, support of backend and middleware api rest services in an event driven architecture handle asynchronous kafka queues (pub-sub and observer patterns), using mainly Java 8, hibernate, maria db, docker, respositories on Github and cloud infraestructure over aws and pipelines ci/cd with jenkins.

TLTR: aditional technologies used -> telesign, scala, aws aurora, postman, kibana, SQL, dropwizard, spring, querydsl, mongodb, Apache Solr, Apache Redis, Memcached, Grafana, New Relic, linux and bash scripting, trust service siftscience, camel and zookeeper to handle kafka cluster, parallel programming on java always using scrum methodology

Java Developer / Application Support

Consis International

Jun 2013 - Jun 2016 (3 years 1 month)

Application support, Client in La Paz, Bolivia, handling: Java J2EE, Weblogic, Hibernate, SVN, PL / Sql, Vaadin, GWT, Wicket, Scrum, Deal with client, Insurance, Policy, Claim, Ant, Maven direct deal with client. bilingual.

Programador Java Semi Senior

Bandatec C.A.

Sep 2012 - Apr 2013 (8 months)

Java application development, Grails, designed to allow tracking of units by satellite tracking. intensive use of Google Maps API

Analista de seguridad

Banco Sofitasa

Sep 2011 - Oct 2012 (1 year 2 months)

Security Analist.

Desarrollador Jr.

Fintec LLC

Jul 2010 - Sep 2011 (1 year 3 months)

Development of applications for electronic banking, Web Services, GRAILS, As400, J2EE

♦™ Consultor Jr.

ITBC Group

Jun 2010 - Jul 2010 (2 months)

System Administrator, DBA, Software Integration

Education

A 11m

Universidad Nacional Experimental del Táchira

Ingeniero, Informatica

2004 - 2010

- * In 2004 he began studies
- * In 2005 he obtained recognition of the Practical Ingenuity in Programming Days 1 for the Game of Tanks project developed in JAVA, Swing.
- * In 2006 it is part of the Caronte Astronomical Center attached to the Research Deanship, it is also part of the group of facilitators of Induction courses for new students.
- * In 2009 Presents Thesis "Application to solve the problem of the ECC on a Grid architecture using Globus Toolkit" Achieving publication mention and honorable mention.
- * In 2010 he obtained the title of Computer Engineer

Licenses & Certifications

- Fluidez de Duolingo en alemán: Principiante (Estimado) Duolingo
- Fluidez de Duolingo en inglés: Avanzado (Estimado) Duolingo
- **Certificate of Completion: Java Course** Sololearn 1068-3477577
- Certificate of Completion: SQL Fundamentals Sololearn 1060-3477577
- Scrum Fundamentals Certified SCRUMstudy Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile
 563954
- Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services Coursera VNK2BHJ2GHYZ
- Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation Coursera

KCMAQK5LSW5N

in Advanced Design Patterns: Design Principles - LinkedIn

Skills

Java EE • Hibernate • Java • SQL • JavaScript • Atlassian JIRA • Linux • MySQL • jQuery • Microsoft SQL Server